Register of the Arch Carey Papers, 1912-1967
Hoover Institution Archives
Arch Carey Papers,
1912-1967
81102
Carey, Arch, 1893-
3 manuscript boxes (1.2 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Memoirs, other writings, printed matter, and photographs, relating to social conditions in China, especially during World War II.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Access Points
British--China; World War, 1939-1945; World War, 1939-1945--China; China--Social conditions; Great Britain
Container List
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1946-1967 (Box 1.)
  - Notes on China, n.d. Holographs and typescripts
  - "The Almond-Eyed Lady," n.d. Holograph. Includes critique by Glenn Clairmonte, 1949. Typescript
  - "Asia and World Politics," n.d. Holograph and typescript
  - "Birth of Communism in China Following the Reign of the War Lords," n.d. Holograph
  - "China, 1893-1904," n.d. Typescript (carbon copy)
  - "China Today," 1951. Typescript
  - "Chinese Painting," n.d. Typescript
  - "Contributory Causes of Present Unrest in China," 1948. Typescript
  - "Easy Money," n.d. Holograph
  - "Formosa," n.d. Typescript
  - "Oil Operations in China," 1949. Typescript (carbon copy)
  - "Peking," 1951. Typescript and carbon copy
  - "Shanghai Diary," 1946 Holograph
  - "Suspense," n.d. Holograph
  - "A Yangtse Voyage," n.d. Holograph
  - The War Years at Shanghai, 1941-45-48, New York, Vantage Press, 1967
  - Printed copy
  - Manuscript A, 1948. Typescript
    - Part 1
    - Part 2
  - Manuscript B, 1949. Typescript (Box 2.)
    - Part 1
    - Part 2
  - Manuscript C, 1949. Typescript
    - Part 1
    - Part 2
- SUBJECT FILE, 1916/1948-1960
  - Biographical File
  - China
  - Shanghai Fire Department
- PHOTOGRAPH FILE, 1912-1925 (Box 3.)
  - Three photograph albums depicting the Shanghai Fire Department, general scenes of China. Includes numerous photographs of friends and relatives in China and Great Britain